MICHAEL ROCKHOLD

Developer ∼ Engineer

CV

m@rockhold.co

michaelrockhold

(206) 240-6636

Seattle WA

in michaelrockhold

SUMMARY

I'm a senior software developer with a wide range of experience and interests. I have a high degree of skill and experience in native mobile application development as well as in the design and development of backend microservices suitable for supporting those mobile apps. I am motivated by opportunities to learn new things and to share those learnings with colleagues and collaborators.

SKILLS

Languages: Swift / C/C++ / Objective-C / Python / Java / Go / Pascal

Tools: git / GitLab CI/CD / GitHub Pages / TestFlight / Xcode / VSCode

Linux / macos / iOS / UIKit / AppKit / MapKit / SwiftUI / Core Data / Core Technologies:

Graphics / AWS / Creating REST APIs / Algorithms / Raspberry Pi

Activities:

· System Design

· Requirements gathering

Sprint planning

· Design review, code review

· Planning, creating, and executing automated test cases and UI automation

· Agile Development practices

Test Driven Development

· Recruitment activities including candidate assessment, interviewing, and interview design

· Brown-bag presentations

Conference presentations

• Strong Communication and Presentation Skills, written and oral

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

10 months

9/2022 - 7/2023 Software Engineer

Sinclair Digital

Video Service Engineering team

- Designed, developed and deployed middleware to support streaming video services' customer sign-up and subscription service
- \cdot Designed and developed a system that automates the connection of live station news feeds to Facebook Live and other social media streaming services
- · Designed, developed, and put into service a cloud-based search engine for KOMO TV's archive of daily run-down sheets going back decades
- · Coded in primarily in Java, JavaScript, and Terraform to build and deploy web APIs using Spring Boot and other frameworks
- Debugged my APIs across service boundaries
- Subject matter expert for APIs in my area of responsibility
- · Collaborated with teams across the company, consulting with developers on other teams to share code, establish interfaces, distribute labor
- · Wrote clear, concise, and testable code
- Provided valuable unit and integration tests;
- · Contributed meaningful feedback in peer code reviews
- Mentored junior developers
- · Interviewed developer candidates for recruitment to our team or to others.

9/2019 - 9/2022 34 months

Software Engineer

Sinclair Digital

Innovation Lab (now sadly defunct)

- · Proposed projects
- Presented plans, progress, and results on a regular basis to Steering Committee, the C-suite audience that commissions and evaluates our work
- · Authored development and test plans
- · Wrote clear, concise, and testable code
- · Coded in primarily in Go, GraphQL, and Python, some Javascript with React and React Native
- · Developed unit and integration tests for new code
- · Used cloud tools like ElasticSearch, AWS Lambda, AWS CloudFormation, AWS S3, AWS SNS, etc.
- Wrote Terraform scripts to deploy to AWS via GitHub and GitLab CI/CD systems
- Designed and developed a simple middleware to be a single coherent API for our clients to use exclusively, which coordinates and orchestrates access to a number of different services, both internal and external to Sinclair
- Used AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, ECS, API Gateway, S3, Simple Notification Service, Route 53 to build micro services
- Developed custom middleware to support web and React Native clients for a prototype of a new Sinclair news property

7/2017 - 4/2019 21 months

Sr. Software Engineer

Hestan Smart Cooking, Inc.

- · Designed, coded Meat Tempering feature
- · Designed, coded an improved Bluetooth cooking device discovery and pairing system
- Proposed and led a major refactor of much of the iOS app to employ a MVVM pattern that improved the maintainability and extensibility of the code.
- · Diagnosed and corrected bugs
- · Reviewed code in ObjC, Swift, Java for iOS and Android apps and web services deployed on AWS
- Developed manual and automated test processes
- · Interviewed and assessed candidates for recruitment

7/2012 - 5/2017 58 months

Software Engineer III

Nordstrom. Inc.

- · Designed, coded a map-based Store Search feature to help draw customers into the stores
- Helped spearhead the transition of the whole Customer Mobile Application team to Test-Driven Development and Full Pair Programming
- · Presented brown-bag talks frequently to share learnings from remote training sessions
- Developed prototype apps to explore potential product ideas
- · Diagnosed and corrected bugs
- Reviewed code in Objective-C, Swift, and Java for iOS and Android apps, and web services deployed on AWS
- Developed manual and automated test processes
- · Lead development of a new style of candidate interview using pair programming and TDD.
- Interviewed and assessed candidates for recruitment

7/2011 - 6/2012 **Software Developer**

Ascentium, Inc.

2/2009 - 9/2013 **Owner, Developer**

Rockhold Company.

4/1996 - 1/2009 Software Design Engineer III

Microsoft, Inc.

10/1994 - 4/1996 **Software Developer**

Attachmate Corporation

1991 – 1994 Lead Quality Assurance Engineer

Developer

MUMPS Developer

Symantec Corporation
InterSystems, Inc.

VERTEK, Inc.

EDUCATION -

1988 - 1991

1987 - 1988

9/2015 - 1/2019 Master of Science

University of Washington

McGill University

Bachelor of Arts

9/1981 - 1/1986

Linguistics, C.S. minor, 2.7 GPA

Computer Science and Engineering, 3.3 GPA

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Coding Georg https://github.com/appel-rockhold/georg

A macOS desktop and iPadOS app for sharing editable map documents

Coding Micropolis Experiment https://github.com/michaelrockhold/micropolis

 $Hacking \ on \ the \ Sim City \ 1.0 \ code base \ to \ test \ out \ some \ ideas \ for \ games. \ One \ part \ of \ this \ is \ making \ a \ Swift UI$

app for macos, and another is making a version of Micropolis for the Playdate console.

Coding HexMap https://github.com/michaelrockhold/Hexasphere-sw

the Game of Life but on a hex-tiled globe instead of a 2D grid of square cells

HOBBIES

Homemaking Cooking, Baking

I enjoy adapting recipes from various tradtions and cuisines to be vegetarian or vegan.

DIY remodeling Attic Sauna

I built a good-sized cedar-lined sauna in some unimproved space in the attic of my house during the

pandemic without ruining anything

Home Automation CoffeeSwitch

Cartography Hacks TransitScope

designed an electronic switch controlled by HomeKit, and installed it in our coffemaker so that we could

start the coffee from our phones before getting out of bed.

Home Automation Doorbell Notifications

the front doorbell doesn't ring, it sends a push notification to all our phones

see near-real-time locations of all buses in the King County Metro system (sadly defunct due to retirement

https://github.com/michaelrockhold/TransitScope

of a key API)

LANGUAGES

English - native, French - B1, German - B1, Spanish - B1